In case of a medical emergency, health
insurance covers our hospital and medical
expenses. However,
many serious illnesses, or critical illnesses, have
very high medical costs, making it
difficult to get coverage even with health insurance. On the one hand, we incur the cost
of treatment, while on the
other hand, our household
expenses, such as loans and other expenses, also become a burden.
In the case of such a critical illness, it becomes
very difficult to continue our job, business, or profession.
We are forced to stay at home for a long time.
In such cases, a critical
insurance policy proves to be very helpful because it covers a serious
illness,
which we can use for our treatment or
other expenses.
In this category, the Tata
Team Medicare plan is one of the best plans.
Today, we will take a deep dive into this
insurance plan and see why it is the
best. This plan is
available in four sections: Section A, Critical,
Section B, Cancer 360 Cover, Section C.
Hospital Cash: These three sections are the base
section, from which we have to take one section,
or we can take two, or we
can select all three. The
section
for benefits is given, which is optional, which we
can take along with the base cover. The first section is
critical. Let's look at its features.
This plan is available in two variants:
Smart Century Premier Plan and
Smart Half Century Plan. The Smart
Century Premier Plan covers 100 critical
diseases, while the Half Century Plan
covers 50 critical diseases. If
any of the listed diseases is detected in the policy, the
payout of our insured is lump
sum.
We get the option of preventive health checkup,
for which we get one percent of our summation, maximum up
to Rs 10,000.
A very unique feature of this plan is
Smart Cancer Care.
Critical is
separate and separate. The second most important
thing is that the cancer is diagnosed
according to the stage,
30% is given.  The
option of medical opinion is available in
this plan. The biggest feature of this plan is its
USP and unique selling point. The
multiple pay feature is that if any critical is
detected, the sum insured is used
and the policy is closed.
However, this plan is
divided into categories listed in categories A, B
and C. Century Premier Plan
covers 39 diseases in category A, 33DC and categories limited to 28 diseases.
Smart Half Century Plan
covers 17 diseases in category B and 17 diseases in category C. While
we can claim once in each category, there is a
waiting period of 60 days for claiming in other categories.
Once we claim in all three categories, the
policy is closed. The
best thing is that we can
claim not only the amount for which we have taken cover, but also for all the
three categories.
Suppose there is a cover of Rs. 10 lakh, then for the category
also we can claim Rs. 10 lakh.  You can claim
for Category B as well as Category
C.
If you claim for Category A in the Smart Century Premier Plan, the
premium for the next three years is waived. Up
to 70% of your premium is
waived for the next three years. The
next feature is the survival period.
Survival period means that
after a critical illness is diagnosed, the policyholder must
survive for the survival period.
If the patient dies before the survival period, the
policy benefits are not paid out.
In this plan, we get a survival period of 15 days,
but by
paying a small extra premium, we can extend this
survival period to 7 days or even zero
days. This feature is
very important in such cases. Many
times we have seen people die suddenly
due to heart attack or stroke,
without even getting time to go to the hospital. In such cases, there is a zero-
day survival period.  It is very useful. The
next section is Cancer 360.
Cancer 360 is an indemnity cover. Indemnity
cover means that it covers hospital-
related medical expenses. These
medical expenses are
related to cancer treatment, which include inpatient treatment, day care
treatment, home care, chemotherapy,
radiotherapy, advanced treatment for cancer,
high-end diagnostics, psychiatric
counseling, global cover, and other benefits
such as pre- and post-hospitalization, organ donor expenses,
OPD cover, hotel accommodation,
transport, station express, ambulance
cover, first active care health checkup, second
medical opinion, and consumer benefits. The
next
section covers cash benefits,
which include inpatient hospitalization. A
canvas cash benefit of more than 10 days is available. If the hospitalization is
inpatient in the ICU, the inpatient cash benefit is doubled. If the hospitalization is
due to an accident, the
inpatient cash benefit is doubled.
And if the hospitalization is in the ICU due to an accident, the
ICU cash
benefit is doubled.  The
next section is of range benefit
which is an optional benefit. In this section,
we get lumpsum payout according to the list for some minor and major surgeries. Along with this, there is
also an optional benefit for personal accident in
which we get a payout of Rs 3 lakh in case of accidental death. The
minimum entry age of this plan is 18 years and
maximum age is 65 years. The initial
waiting period is 90 days, which means that
its coverage starts after 90 days of taking the policy. There is a
waiting period of 48 months for free existing diseases.
If any disease is already there, then it is
covered after 4 years. This was about Tata Aayegi
Medicare Critical Illness Insurance Plan.
If you have any doubt or query related to this plan,
health insurance, life
insurance or insurance,
you can ask us by commenting below or by
messaging on the WhatsApp number given below.
That's all for today's video,
friends. See you in the next video.  I
thank you